A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Office Files of Elinor Barber FA632
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Appendix B: Reports: Women's Status/Roles/Opportunities
  - Barber, Elinor G./Saario, Terry. Visit to Radcliffe Institute, 1975 December (Report 7777)
  - Barber, Elinor G./Saario, Terry. Visit to Wellesley Center, 1975 December (Report 7778)
  - Barber, Elinor G. AID conference on women in development, 1975 November (Report 7779)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Wellesley and Wingspread Conferences, 1976 June (Report 7780)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Seminar on African women in rural development, 1976 May (Report 7781)
  - Silverstein, Leni M. Recommendation for "A" status for a women's program in Brazil, 1980 April (Report 7782)
  - Gardner, James A. Sao Paulo trip notes: visit to Pro Mulher, 1978 August (Report 7784)
  - Myers, Robert G. Meeting to discuss research on the status of women in Colombia, Venezuela, and Peru, 1974 March (Report 7785)
  - Trottenberg, Arthur D. Progress report - affirmative action, 1972 November (Report 7786)
  - Trottenberg, Arthur D. Employment of women and minorities on the professional staff, 1972 April (Report 7788)
  - Barber, Elinor G./Germain, Adrienne. The Percy Amendment, 1974 May (Report 7789)
  - Dunlop, Joan. Whither women and development?, 1981 May (Report 7790)
  - Carden, Maren Lockwood. Survey of new feminist organizations-- progress report, 1975 July (Report 7791)
  - Saario, Terry. Sex discrimination - the big new problem for boards, 1973 April (Report 7802)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Minutes of meeting Dec. 6, 1974, with Esther Boserup, 1975 January (Report 7803)
  - Germain, Adrienne. (Session in Cali, Colombia; meeting of Population advisors, reps, various NY staff): Session IX, "Status of women". (Report 7804)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Irrigation: making it useful for disadvantaged groups, 1980 October (Report 7807)
  - Germain, Adrienne/Weisblat, Abe. Planning session on water management 10/23/80, 1980 October (Report 7835)
  - Flora, Cornelia Butler. Request for "A" status for a supplemental DAP on research on women and development in the Andean Region and the Southern Cone (769-0825), 1979 June (Report 7836)
  - Germain, Adrienne. The International Division's work on women's roles in development, 1976 October (Report 7837)
  - Goodwillie, Susan. The Ford Foundation and women, 1976 April (Report 7838)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Curriculum for professionals dealing with rural women, 1980 December (Report 7839)
  - Zollner, Joy. (Kenya - sex differences in education) (Report 7840)
  - McKee,Katharine. Women contacts at Universities of Ibadan, Ife and Lagos, 1979 January (Report 7841)
  - McKee, Katharine. Progress on Women's DAP and related developments, 1979 November (Report 7842)
  - McKee, Katharine. The Association for the Study of Women in Africa (ASOWA), 1979 June (Report 7844)
  - Pappas, Linda M. Programming for women in the Middle East, 1975 May (Report 7845)
  - Zeidenstein, George. Women in Bangladesh, 1973 November (Report 7846)
  - Mayo, Molly. Research - prospects for program development, 1976 April (Report 7848)
  - Mayo, Molly. Confidential impressions of International Seminar on Women, Islamabad, Nov. 10-15, 1975, 1975 November 10 - 15 (Report 7849)
  - Mayo, Molly. (Seminar on "Role and status of women", Pakistan Administrative Staff College, 29-31 October, 1975.), 1975 October 29 - 31 (Report 7850)
  - Del Castillo, Solita. Women participation in currently supported programs, projects and awards. (Report 7852)
  - Rixhon, Gerry. Visit of Ms. Elinor G. Barber to the Philippines, 1977 October (Report 7853)
  - Chambers, Robert/Lenton, Roberto. Note on irrigation and women, 1981 February (Report 7856)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Visit to India and Indonesia, 1981 April (Report 7857)
  - De Leal, Magdalena/de Rodriguez. History and conditions of female labor force participation in Colombia, 1975 December (Report 7858)
  - Redclift, Nanneke Codd. Request for "A" status approval, delegated authority project for research, training, and applied projects relating to the position of women in Mexico and Central America, 1980 March (Report 7859)
  - Barber, Elinor G. The Brazilian women's program, 1980 April (Report 7860)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Discussions in Paris of research on women, 1976 September (Report 7867)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Trip to Colombia and Brazil - July 1974, 1974 August (Report 7868)
  - Knowles, Marjorie F. Review of Foundation-funded women's research centers, 1980 December (Report 7869)
  - Spangenberg, Gail. Continuing education and women, 1973 January (Report 7871)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Visits to Berkeley and Stanford, 1976 March (Report 7872)
  - Sundar, Pushpa. Women: problems, perspectives, and programs for development (Report 7876)
  - Jones, Sidney. Trip report - India: Feb. 6-19, 1979 March (Report 7877)
  - Bell, David E. Untitled letter to Patricia M. Wald re: affirmative action in the International Division, 1974 September (Report 7878)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Trip to the Philippines, Pakistan, Bangladesh, and India - March 1975, 1975 May (Report 7880)
  - Bettles, F.M. Women's access to agricultural extension services in Botswana, 1980 April (Report 7881)
  - Boulding, Elise. Women's Task Force meeting with Elise Boulding (November 10, 1972)., 1972 November 10 (Report 7884)
  - Rainwater, Lee. Transcript of Women's Task Force meeting with Professor Lee Rainwater, Department of Sociology, Harvard, 1972 October 25 (Report 7885)
  - Schachter, Esther Roditti et al. Women - a priority area for the Ford Foundation in the 198O's, 1976 October (Report 7888)
  - Barber, Elinor G. The International Division's Women's Program information paper, 1979 January (Report 7889)
  - Mirza, Anis. Discussion paper: Pakistani women's status - problems, 1976 April (Report 7908)
  - Dirasse, Laketch. Workshop on women's access to educational opportunities in Eastern Africa, 1980 March (Report 7909)
  - Barber, Elinor G./Goodwillie, Susan. Visit to Nigeria, Nov. 3-10, 1976, 1976 December (Report 7910)
  - Reyes, Petra. Regional conference on the implementation of national, regional, and world plans of action for the integration of women in development, Nouakchott, Mauritania, 27 Sept-- 20 Oct- 1977, 1977 October (Report 7911)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Impressions of the status of women in Japan (Report 7915)
  - Iwao, Sumiko. Untitled letter to Carl Green re: trip to China, 1980 May (Report 7916)
  - Redman, Linda J. Discretionary grants - Asia and Pacific Division, concern for women, 1975 January (Report 7917)
  - Assaad, Marie. Equality, development, and peace; education, employment, health; MidDecade for Women; Non-Governmental Organizations (NGO) Forum. (Report 7918)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Interviews in Nairobi on the status of women in Kenya Feb. 1-15, 1974, 1974 March (Report 7923)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Trip to Tanzania - status and roles of women, 1974 March (Report 7924)
  - Barber, Elinor G. West Africa visit, February 1980, 1980 April (Report 7925)
  - Elmendorf/Trimble. The changing status of women: Mexico, 1973 November (Report 7929)
  - Dirasse, Laketch. The critical needs of African women (Report 7930)
  - Berger, Margaret A. Litigation on behalf of women: an assessment, 1979 March (Report 7933)
  - Barber, Elinor G. (Access to women's education in rural areas), 1979 December (Report 7997)
  - Goodwillie, Susan. Donor review of the Economic Commission for Africa's African Training and Research Center for Women (March 6-24, 1978), 1978 April (Report 8001)
  - Ainan, Catherine M. The need for appropriate education and evaluation of women education programmes, 1980 March (Report 8002)
  - Mvungi, M.V. Women's access to higher education: Tanzanian experience, 1980 March (Report 8003)
  - Womens access to nonformal education: the experience of Tanzania, 1980 March (Report 8004)
  - Opiyo, Mary. Two Kenya case studies on women's development and literacy projects (Report 8005)
  - Background material: affirmative action, 1977 March (Report 8007)
  - Interim report on the expanded Women's Program, 1981 February (Report 8008)
  - Method, Francis J. Thoughts on research and action on the status and roles of women (stimulated by A. Germain's paper and International Division's seminar March 15, 1974) (Report 8009)
  - Report of the Subcommittee on Training for the Affirmative Action Advisory Committee, 1977 February (Report 8010)
  - Trottenberg, Arthur D. The Ford Foundation as an affirmative action employer (Report 8011)
  - Franck/Streibert. The issue of inequality in pension benefits for men and women, 1976 July (Report 8012)
  - Schachter, Esther Roditti. The issue of inequality in pension benefits for men and women, 1977 April (Report 8013)
  - Schachter, Esther Roditti/Coordinating Committee on Women's Programs. Supplementary memorandum to interim report on "Equal pensions" (April 1977), 1977 June (Report 8014)
  - Schoenbrod/Freedman. Transcript of Women's Task Force Meeting, May 31, 1973, 1973 May 31 (Report 8146)
  - Aguilar, Art. Brief report on status of women in the Philippines (Report 8148)
  - Rosser, Colin. Task force on the status of women, 1977 October (Report 8149)
  - Antrobus, Peggy. Women - the challenge of the Eighties: a new perspective on development, 1980 March (Report 8152)
  - Report on the Workshop on Arab Women Studies, Wellesley, June 6-8, 1976., 1976 June 6 - 8 (Report 8154)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Copenhagen Forum, 1980 July (Report 8157)
  - Cole, Jonathan R. American men and women of science (Report 8158)
  - Elliott, Carolyn. Women functionaries, 1981 April (Report 8159)
  - The Ford Foundation and equality of opportunity for women (Report 8172)
  - Graham, Patricia Albjerg. Women in higher education: a report to the Ford Foundation, 1977 February (Report 8173)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Poor rural women: a policy perspective, 1971 February (Report 8174)
  - Cool, John. The status of women, the Foundation, and India, 1972 September (Report 8176)
  - Smock, Audrey C. The implications of Kenya's high rate of population growth, 1979 November (Report 8179)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Bali irrigation and related development project, ADB, appraisal mission: consultancy, 14 Feb-13 April 1978, 1978 April (Report 8199)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Institute for Women's Studies in the Arab World, visit Feb. 2, 1979, 1979 February (Report 8200)
  - D'Souza, Stanislaus. Travel report, 1978 December (Report 8213)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Report on visit to Botswana, April 13-17, 1980, 1980 April (Report 8214)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Programming for women in FY74, staff meeting Dec. 9, 1975, 1975 December (Report 8215)
  - Jahan, Rounaq. The IXth International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences held in Chicago, Aug. 29 - Sept. 8, 1973, 1973 November (Report 8216)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Report on Lima visit, 2/5/75 - 2/18/75, 1975 April (Report 8217)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Future International Division programming on women, 1976 October (Report 8218)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Regional South and Southeast Asia Seminar on Women and Development, March 28 - April 1, 1977, 1977 April (Report 8219)
  - UNECA. Women and national development in African countries: some profound contradictions, 1973 February (Report 8221)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Women's Division, Cabinet Secretariat, Pakistan, 1980 June (Report 8223)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Outcome of Philippines visit, Oct. 12-18, 1977, 1978 January (Report 8224)
  - Germain, Adrienne. My work in 1977, 1978 January (Report 8225)
  - Reagan, Barbara. Economic foundation of women in the labor market, 1980 September (Report 8228)
  - Barber, Elinor G. The International Division's Women's Program information paper, 1979 January (Report 8229)
  - Flora, Cornelia Butler. Women in Latin American fotonovelas: from Cinderella to Mata Hari, 1979 May (Report 8230)
  - Flora, Cornelia Butler. Evaluation of Seminar on Women in the Labor Force in Latin America, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1978 November 23 - 26 (Report 8231)
- Appendix C: Reports: Education/Language/Development
  - Noss, Richard B. Politics and language policy, 1970 July (Report 1702)
  - Finkelstein, David. Korea, 1975 June (Report 2044)
  - Ford Foundation. Rural development and employment, 1973 April (Report 2175)
  - Sutton/Smock. The Ford Foundation and African studies, 1975 November (Report 2168)
  - Nicholas, Ralph W. Social science research in Bangladesh, 1973 December (Report 2178)
  - Ford Foundation. International Affairs. Ford Foundation activities Teaching English as a Second Language, 1962 (Report 2303)
  - Edwards, Edgar O. Employment in developing countries: report on a Ford Foundation study, 1974 July (Report 2678)
  - Fox, Melvin J. et al. The Ford Foundation's overseas activities in language fields - meetings and discussion papers, 1971 (Report 2727)
  - Nelson, Courtney A. Musings on the Middle East program, 1976 September (Report 3130)
  - McLean, Sheila Avrin. The Republic of South Africa, 1976 December (Report 3255)
  - Cyr, Arthur. The program of studies in Public Policy and Social Organization, 1974 June (Report 3489)
  - Prator, Clifford H. The survey of language use and language teaching in Eastern Africa: inceptions and initial activities, 1978 October (Report 3582)
  - Prator, Clifford H. Retrospective survey of seven language-related projects supported by the Ford Foundation in North Africa and the Middle East, 1973 April - September (Report 3514)
  - McCord, Colin. What's the use of a demonstration project, 1976 November (Report 3712)
  - Chen, Lincoln C. et al. Recent fertility trends in Bangladesh: speculation on the role of biological factors and socioeconomic change, 1976 December (Report 3713)
  - Chowdhury/Chen. The dynamics of contemporary famine, 1977 January (Report 3714)
  - Khatun/Rani. Bari-based post harvest operations and livestock care: some observations and case studies, 1977 December (Report 3715)
  - Abdulaziz, Mohamed H. Evaluation report on survey of language use and language teaching of Eastern Africa, 1978 September (Report 3865)
  - Flora, Cornelia Butler. Child care in Nicaragua, 1980 November (Report 3960)
  - Ward, F. Champion. Assistance to education in the seventies, 1971 September (Report 3974)
  - The language activities and interests of the International Division, 1971 October (Report 3975)
  - Fox, Melvin J. The changing role of the Ford Foundation in relation to language education in developing countries, 1974 May (Report 4131)
  - Chafkin, Sol H. Significant, complicated, neglected: the nutrition factor affecting Foundation programs, 1979 May (Report 4200)
  - Ford Foundation. International migration and refugees, 1980 March (Report 4711)
  - Barber/Ilchman. International Studies review: a staff study, 1979 September (Report 4764)
  - McCaughey, Robert A. International studies and the university: a chapter in the enclosure of American learning, 1977 (Report 5096)
  - McCaughey, Robert A. Report on the Symposium on Affirmative Action in higher education, 1974 December (Report 5586)
  - Human rights and intellectual freedom, 1978 March (Report 5724)
  - Wald, Patricia. Some reactions from my trip to Niger, Nigeria, South Africa, Kenya, India, Thailand, South Vietnam, Japan, 1974 September (Report 5836)
  - Gardner, James A. Politics in Brazil: contradictions in the "miracle" and the difficult transition from authoritarianism to "redemocratization". (Report 6038)
  - Martus, Marjorie. Notes on bilingual education, 1975 April (Report 6047)
  - Taylor, Lance et al. Food subsidy programs: a survey, 1980 December (Report 6185)
  - Wald, Patricia M. Some observations on the survival of children around the world, 1974 August (Report 6302)
  - Mundigo, Axel M. Population policy in Brazil: recent changes, 1977 October (Report 6350)
  - Korten, David C. Community organization and rural development: a learning process approach, 1980 April (Report 6374)
  - Horowitz, Donald L. Achieving minorities and ethnic conflict, 1977 July (Report 6387)
  - Sutton, Francis X. The international liaison of universities: history, hazards, and opportunities, 1979 (Report 6433)
  - Seckler, David. Sukhomajri: a rural development program in India, 1981 March (Report 6665)
  - Germain, Adrienne. ADC/ICRISAT seminar, "Adjustment mechanisms in rural labor markets.", 1979 September (Report 7014)
  - Simmons, Ozzie G. Health/Nutrition/Population activities in Indonesia, 1980 December (Report 7083)
  - Knowles, James C. Interactions between malnutrition and disease: a simultaneous equations model applied to data from a low-income area of Karachi, 1979 September (Report 7105)
  - A gloss on Fox: some implications of the Fox report for Foundation activitites in the language field and proposals for follow-up, 1978 January (Report 7118)
  - Gardner, James A. A question of values, 1976 December (Report 7559)
  - Scribner/Cole. Cognitive consequences of formal and informal education (Report 7675)
  - Selowsky/Taylor. The economics of malnourished children: an example of disinvestment in human capital, 1973 October (Report 7676)
  - Hanratty, Martin. The development of a pilot program in intensive homestead agro-forestry, n.d. (Report 7677)
  - Harkavy, Oscar. Some notes on Ford Foundation Population meeting, Cali, Colombia, October 14-18, 1974, 1974 December (Report 7681)
  - Mertens, Walter. National meeting on population - Tarma, Peru - June 25-29, 1979, n.d. (Report 7701)
  - Fagen, Richard R. Untitled report on Sandinista movement in Nicaragua, 1980 July (Report 7702)
  - Coatswith, Ray. Establishing a rural development programme in Eastern Nigeria, 1968 October (Report 7726)
  - Schoettle, Enid. Progress report of PPSO Task Force on the Military and Society, 1980 November (Report 7748)
  - Sharpe, Richard S. IIEP/SIDA Seminar on Planning Problems in Rural Education, Paris, 13-17 October 1975, 1975 October 13 - 17 (Report 7755)
  - Lesch, Ann M. Visit to UCLA, 1979 March (Report 7756)
  - Starr, John Bryan. Report of interviews at Columbia University in conjunction with Ford Foundation and NEH Survey of colleges and universities regarding programs in international education (1-2 Feb. 1979) (Report 7757)
  - Starr, John Bryan. Report of interviews at the University of Chicago in conjunction with Ford Foundation and NEH survey of colleges and universities regarding programs in international education (8-9 Feb. 1979) (Report 7758)
  - Gaer, Felice D. Summary of International Studies visits, 1979 May (Report 7759)
  - Himes, James R. Visit to Yale University, International Studies Review, January 29-30, 1979, 1979 March (Report 7760)
  - Gaberman, Barry D. Interviews at Michigan State University (February 20-21, 1979), n.d. (Report 7761)
  - Gaberman, Barry D. Interviews at Tulane University (March 1-2, 1979), n.d. (Report 7762)
  - Cooper, Robert L. Language planning, language spread, and language change, 1978 September (Report 7792)
  - Lewis, E. Glyn. Movement and agencies of language spread - Wales and the Soviet Union compared, 1978 September (Report 7793)
  - Haynes, Lilith M./Tucker, Richard. Program in Language Education for the Middle East region, 1977 February (Report 7794)
  - Pool, Jonathan. Proceedings: International Conference on the Methodology of Sociolinguistic Surveys, Montreal, Quebec, Canada, May 1975, n.d. (Report 7796)
  - Fox, Melvin J. CIEFL Evaluation study, 1974 August (Report 7797)
  - Schuman, Barry. International Studies at Cornell, 1979 February (Report 7798)
  - Gaer, Felice D. International Studies REview: visit to Harvard University - dinner with senior faculty - 3/7/79, n.d. (Report 7799)
  - Gaer, Felice D. International Studies Review: meeting with Karl Deutsch, Committee on International Studies and Stanfield Professor of International Peace, Harvard University - 3/9/79. (Report 7800)
  - Gaer, Felice D. Summary of International Studies visits, 1979 May (Report 7801)
  - Ford Foundation. Office for Andes Region and Southern Cone. Toward a program of child development and child care in Latin America, 1980 September (Report 7805)
  - Rice, Marion J. Harijan Wasti, 1980 July (Report 7806)
  - Kale, Pratia. Experiments in education for rural development, 1975 February (Report 7847)
  - Ford Foundation (Bangkok Office). Review of Foundation assistance for educational research, planning and experimentation in Thailand, 1980 March (Report 7851)
  - Fry, Gerald W. The educational correlates of occupational attainment: a Bangkok case study of large-scale organizations (an abstract), 1976 August (Report 7854)
  - Ford Foundation (Bangkok Office). The Ford Foundation in Thailand, 1977 October (Report 7855)
  - Chowdhry, Kamla. Non-formal education and development, 1979 September (Report 7912)
  - Pappas, Linda M. Egypt: trip report -- May 25 - June 5, 1974, 1974 July (Report 7919)
  - Ward, F. C. Visit to India, Dacca, Bangkok, Indonesia, Feb. 25, 1977 - April 8, 1977 (Report 7920)
  - Geithner, Peter F. Program budget - fiscal years 1978 and 1979, Bangkok office, 1977 January (Report 7921)
  - Bausch, James J. Sweden; population policies, 1971 August (Report 7922)
  - Szanton, David L. Proposed research conceptualization seminars (Report 7927)
  - Myers, Robert G. Asia travels, March 10 - April 9, 1977: an overview, 1977 May (Report 7928)
  - Barber, Elinor G. The sociolinguistics scene, 1977 October (Report 7996)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Rural education, 1979 October (Report 7998)
  - Sutton, F. X. November 1978 "Bellagio" Education Meeting, 1978 December (Report 7999)
  - Barber/Ilchman. Barbara Burn's meeting on advanced training and research, 1978 November (Report 8000)
  - Ford Foundation. The Philippines under martial law: a brief assessment (Report 8147)
  - McLean, Sheila Avrin. Visit to South Africa, 1987 January (Report 8150)
  - Ashabranner, Brent. The Foundation's Philippine Program, FY76 - 77, 1979 December (Report 8153)
  - Himes, James R. Comment on Professor John Hunter's position paper for Session II: "Development asssistance program", n.d. (Report 8162)
  - Martus, Marjorie/Barber, Elinor G. Visit to the Center, May 18 and 19, 1978 June (Report 8163)
  - Alleyne, Mervyn C. Report on sociolinguistic research in Latin America, n.d. (Report 8164)
  - Noss, Richard B. Review of resources for planning, research and the teaching of language in Malaysia, 1971 May (Report 8165)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Meeting on language, 1971 June (Report 8166)
  - Fox, Melvin J. Notes on conference of the Language Association of Eastern Africa, Limuru, Kenya, 1972 July 7 - 9 (Report 8167)
  - Bamgbose, Ayo, and L. Ayo Banjo. Language Association of Eastern Africa Conference, 7-9 July 1972, Limuru, Kenya - a report for the Ford Foundation, 1972 July 7 - 9 (Report 8168)
  - Noss, Richard B. The regional language situation with reference to Foundation interests, 1972 July (Report 8169)
  - DeCamp, David. Untitled trip report re: consultant visit to Khartoum, 1974 May (Report 8170)
  - Fox, Melvin J. IAI Seminar on African Languages in Education, Kinshasa, 13-15 December 1976, 1977 January (Report 8171)
  - Fox, Melvin J. British-American talks on cooperation in English language teaching, 1978 December (Report 8175)
  - Smock, David. Budget projections for 1980-81, 1978 December (Report 8178)
  - Smock, Audrey C. The implications of Kenya's high rate of population growth, 1979 November (Report 8179)
  - Fox, Melvin J. Some thoughts on language as a factor in basic education in Africa, n.d. (Report 8184)
  - Fox, Melvin J. Language as a factor in development (Report 8185)
  - Noss, Richard B. Scientific and technological vocabulary in the less common languages: some solutions in search of a problem (Report 8186)
  - Ford Foundation. New Delhi office program statement: fiscal years 1981-82, 1980 October (Report 8198)
  - Martus, Marjorie. Public Education grants in language and linguistics: past and projected, 1970 February (Report 8220)